youmart.in 2015-06-14

# Online fresh Meat & Seafood | Buy Meat Online | Buy Fresh Seafood Online | Best Online Grocery Store in Bangalore: YouMart E-Commerce Store

PRIVACY POLICY

We at YouMart acknowledge that you have entrusted some of your personal information with us while signing up. We are very much obliged for the great trust you have with us and reassure you that all your personal information you have given us will be kept securely and with utmost privacy. Below herewith we explain how we use this information and why we are able to assure you the privacy of data.

**Information we collect**

During you first login and while you shop with YouMart you will submit your personal information to us as this is necessary to recognize you and provide you better service. We will treat all information submitted by you in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy and in strict compliance with all Data Protection law. You may be asked to update such information anytime if it is necessary and found incomplete.  
By entering your personal information in the YouMart web site you agree that we are allowed to retain your information and share with any third party company that processes it on our behalf if necessary. 

**What we collect and why**

Our continuous effort to improve our service can be supported only if we are able to understand our customers better. The information we gather from you helps us in our effort to continually improve the service we offer to our customers.

We are able to gather information about our customers in different ways, while you are shopping with us or while communicating with our office. Here is how we gather the information:

  * The first time when you register with us, we ask for information such as your name, e-mail address, delivery address, contact details etc (these are mandatory to proceed registration) and date of birth, marital status, name and DOB of spouse etc (which are optional). If you place an order and wish to pay by card, you will be asked for your credit/debit card details. We keep a record of this information because all this is necessary for us to recognise you as a registered customer and to fulfil the orders you place with us. Storing this information means you do not need to re-enter these details each time you shop.
  * We keep a record of your purchases with us, which will help us to maintain a history of your previous orders enabling you to access them for your reference and re-ordering. We can also create lists of your favourite items to make your shopping experience quicker and more convenient. It also means we can deal a lot quicker with any problems you may experience with your order.
  * Your email, telephone calls or other correspondence with us will also be recorded to help us to track of your likes and dislikes and any problems or concerns you've had with our products or services. Telephone calls made to our Customer Service Helpline may be recorded for monitoring and quality control purposes.

**How we use your personal information**

The information we collect through our website or any correspondence with you will be used to operate and improve the service we offer you. Here is how we use your personal information in our record: 

  * **Order and Delivery -** To keep you updated during handling of your orders and deliveries and be sure that we communicate to the right person.
  * **Marketing -** As part of our marketing we provide periodic communications by post, telephone, SMS, email about features, offers, promotions and events. We may also include offers from outside parties which may be beneficial to our customers.
  * **Products & Services -** To provide information about the various products and services we offer, this will include information about our joint initiatives with third parties for added services to our customers.
  * **Prices and offers -** Information about special offers, promotions, price benefits and savings to our customers. At times YouMart may select a group of customers for promotional offers and we directly communicate to our customers. 
  * **Market research -** to conduct market research, statistical analysis, customer behavior, market trends, customer feedback.
  * **Third party service providers -** For the purpose of focused campaign and promotions we may sometimes approach third party services. Sometimes for other services, like for example we engage agencies to analyse customer information, provide marketing assistance, process credit card payments. We may also seek outside assistance of credit reference agencies, fraud prevention and detection agencies and debt collection agencies as and when required. In all such cases we only provide information that is relevant to perform the function and make sure that the information is used with care.
  * **Protection and fraud -** enable us to avoid malice entrants to our site by identifying our registered and genuine users. Scammers are capable of creating authentic looking, but false websites. Their intention is to tempt users to enter their personal information like name, bank / credit card details etc and later attempt to access the bank account and do fraud transactions.

**Data security**

To ensure that the customer data is secured we use sophisticated technology while processing, transacting or transferring the information. For example Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") encryption technology is used for protection of information in transit for any sensitive transactions such as payments. We reveal only the last four digits of your credit card number in any bills or documents related to your order and payments. The entire credit card details is only transmitted to the appropriate credit card company during the payment processing.

It is the responsibility of the customer not to allow any unauthorised access to your password and to your computer and make sure to sign off every time after using you computer in a shared network or shared computer. 

**Require more information**

If you feel that the information on the personal data and privacy policy we have provided here does not clarify, you may please contact us at director@youmart.in. To see all the information we have about you, and to update the information, you may email us. 

**The Director**  
**YouMart**
